<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Account for Everything Else</title>
    <link>http://itihas.review/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Account for Everything Else</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 08:39:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://itihas.review/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 08:39:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/silence/</guid>
      <description>The covert coming into sight
The slip of dark away from light
The words rethought, rethought, unsaid
The song of tools whose hands are dead
The tree that never fell at all
The tree that is about to fall
The site of work not yet begun
The shape of work that can&amp;rsquo;t be done
Go forth, and train your secret ear
And silence will be all you hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Games</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/war-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 01:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/war-games/</guid>
      <description>Smoke and the burn and the restless mad turn
Of the wheels in my head that all churn out cliches that I somehow don&amp;rsquo;t mind and I somehow don&amp;rsquo;t pause
And a million and one stupid thoughts without cause
And the cleverness I somehow catch when they&amp;rsquo;re listening
And foolishness inside my safe simple mind
And rhymes that need use of the useless word glistening and all of the pretty young thoughts I can find</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oeuvre</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/oeuvre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 01:23:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/oeuvre/</guid>
      <description>I loved. I loved, and I was not I
And you were not you
And we were not two
An oeuvre is written in an hour of the night
And none of it true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/pretty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 01:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/pretty/</guid>
      <description>The prettiest thing that you ever saw
Wasn&amp;rsquo;t as pretty as I am today
Nor half as attractive in most of the ways
It&amp;rsquo;s important to be.
The prettiest I ever was is today
But I&amp;rsquo;m as pretty or prettier every today
Today is a day that I know and I care
And I notice you stare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Once in a While</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/once-in-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 01:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/once-in-a-while/</guid>
      <description>Those we count as friends, know the dates of our funerals
And can write our eulogies.
Let them speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 18:34:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/fear/</guid>
      <description>You know the greatest fear?
The greatest fear is thinking you once thought something that might have changed the world. It&amp;rsquo;s too terrible a truth to face up to. We shy away from it. But you see, I have. I have read the thoughts of people who looked to change it, who succeeded, if in nothing else, in leaving their mark. Many times they are people who did more. And I have thought what they thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adamant</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/adamant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 05:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/adamant/</guid>
      <description>My secret soul that hides between
What parts of my world count as seen
Is sometimes moved
And sometimes bruised
And one day it may die.
All the words I ever knew
Won&amp;rsquo;t give it away to you
It sometimes screams
And sometimes dreams
And does it all alone.
It holds within an ageless ache
Because, you see, it cannot break.
It sometimes sleeps
And else, it weeps.
I feel it in my bones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siren</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/siren/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/siren/</guid>
      <description>It calls to you from the empty space beyond railings. It&amp;rsquo;s there, waiting, between the cars, tangled with the motorbikes, in every gulf of city road and every chasm of dark highway whose surface sings at the stroke of approaching wheels like the strings of a double-bass. It weaves long, slow spells around the piling trash and unwashed sheets of the cubicle you live in, until it convolves the world into a point of fiction; until your bowels don&amp;rsquo;t have anything left to process and the clawing of your belly seems as much a dream as anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Obsession</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/on-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/on-obsession/</guid>
      <description>She tried to picture the quiet of her meditation hall, timeless, without a beat, without a count, with only the steady progression of forms, the position and reposition of the body, every action of muscle corresponding to an action of breath. One began with palms flat against each other, fingers facing up, held against the sternum, pressing into the bone like a knife-edge lightly held in place; knees and back held straight, unmoving but relaxed, still but not rigid; feet together, facing forward, eyes as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/prologue/</guid>
      <description>It was a piece of emptiness that we all drove around - the place where nothing could be built, nothing could be planted, nothing could happen that humans could have a hand in. Satellite imaging gave us all we really knew about the space that we had to skirt, every single day, just to make it to where we needed to be; that was that it was overgrown, and that the foliage was darker than that immediately surrounding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myth</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/myth/</guid>
      <description>To what extent does what we hear about the world shape the way we speak to it? All our lives we’re fed fantasies of the perfect partner, the other half, the feelings of incompleteness that will not manifest until their resolution is immediately present; the problems that you didn’t know existed until their solution was manifest. This gross appropriation on the part of love of every other myth one can find oneself immersed in is nothing short of criminal at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposition</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/exposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/exposition/</guid>
      <description>She was pretty. She knew it, too, and used it shamelessly to her advantage whenever she thought it would give her the slightest edge in anything. Her face was well enough structured, but it was her skin, pale and creamy and only ever charmingly blemished, that did it for her; that and the way she used her face, the expressions. She was petite but healthy-bodied. She attracted attention, but not stares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preludes</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/preludes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/preludes/</guid>
      <description>The problem with the world today is a lack of destruction.
I say this despite knowing that most will find the notion perfectly counterintuitive – and that&amp;rsquo;s the problem: we have come to a place, in our collective psyche, where we find the necessity of destruction counterintuitive. This is far from a natural or healthy state.
Humans aren&amp;rsquo;t born with respect for only creative or preservative processes; we&amp;rsquo;re born without the barriers that tell us not to pull things down, to tear them apart, to kill them or crush them or stomp on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rorschach on Parquet</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/rorschach-on-parquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/rorschach-on-parquet/</guid>
      <description>The dress was two-layered, and baggy around the torso, falling straight from the shoulders and held in place at the waist by an elastic band. On a thinner woman, it might have looked airy or draping.
A much, much thinner woman. An anorexic woman.
From the elastic, it fell nearly to the ground – would have, if not for the heels that acccompanied it, strappy plastic-gloss patents in a shade that brought out the florid pinks of the print flowers vividly against the black backing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inevitable</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/inevitable/</guid>
      <description>My voice cracked, but it was so far past the point where that would have mattered. “You bastard. You bastard. You left anyway. You&amp;rsquo;re going to do this anyway.”
His hand shook, hesitated, but I&amp;rsquo;d never witnessed an action that felt as inevitable as when he lifted it to my cheek. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear to look at the gentleness on his face.
“It isn&amp;rsquo;t me if I don&amp;rsquo;t.”
I covered his hand with mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/red/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/red/</guid>
      <description>Sensation began at my ears, and pulsed through my head like successive underwater explosions; blurred echoes rippled to the edges of my skull, and stirred me from consuming stupor. I&amp;rsquo;d heard somewhere that, once upon a time, underwater cannons were how they recovered a drowned body – the pulse shook it loose.
I became aware of my head in its entirety through the disturbance that consumed it, beginning at the ears and ricocheting in unpredictable ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/conversation/</guid>
      <description>“Conversations always end too soon for me.”
“Do they now.”
I chewed on my lip, trying to frame my answer. “Either it&amp;rsquo;s awesome, it&amp;rsquo;s working, and the other person says it&amp;rsquo;s over out of the blue, or it just peters off, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where it went.” No, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t right. “It&amp;rsquo;s not that they&amp;rsquo;re silent, more that it stops working like it was.”
He seemed perfectly content to stand where he was, looking at me or through me as we went on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/blind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 07:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/blind/</guid>
      <description>We die; we are killed, we are weathered, are felled, are decayed,
We remain living, watching the ghosts that our murders have made
We suffer our punishments at unseen, untouchable hands;
We write our poetry in languages no one else understands.
I look at you, and my mind is unbound, unfettered in storm
Undoing ghost, what were the murders that made such a form?
I write myself over once more for your unseeing eye,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dystopian Story</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/a-dystopian-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 06:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/a-dystopian-story/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Put that cheapot down, Helen.&amp;rdquo;
At the sound of the high-pitched voice, with its imperious tone, Helen jumped so badly that the cornflower-blue teapot nearly fell out of her hands. With hands still shaking, she slotted the teapot back into its hexagonal niche in the wall, and the pneumatic door slid closed in front of it almost before she could withdraw her hands again.
Helen&amp;rsquo;s daughter stood crossly in the doorway, hands on hips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look what the cat dragged in.</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/look-what-the-cat-dragged-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 06:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/look-what-the-cat-dragged-in/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;But I love you,&amp;rdquo; he pleads, eyes streaming and voice shaking; a mess of quaking limbs and blotched skin, dressed in dirty thirdhand rags and alley-cat hair, on his knees on the expensive carpet I had had selected and arranged just last week. I sniff, disgusted. Does he honestly expect his snivelling to make any difference to me? One would have thought he’d know better by now at least.
Gingerly, I brush at a trailing, fraying bit of cloth with a foot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evil Prompter</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/an-evil-prompter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 05:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/an-evil-prompter/</guid>
      <description>Who is the person holding the cue cards
and what does he want today?
Sleep ran off with Night, so I drank with First Light
She washed all my lines away
Sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re blank, and sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re written
in languages I never learned
Sometimes he&amp;rsquo;s filled them with absolute nonsense
And sometimes he&amp;rsquo;s holding them turned
Who is the person holding the cue cards
and what does he want with me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nocturne</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/nocturne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 22:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/nocturne/</guid>
      <description>Long did I travel, from home I was far
When I saw you make love to the evening star
That home I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten, and can&amp;rsquo;t find anew
For my world has faded to that star and you.
Venus is fickle, but her lovers are true
You&amp;rsquo;ve yet to return from wherever you flew.
I&amp;rsquo;ll shadow her—though she seems dark to me too
I&amp;rsquo;ll wait in her darkness to once more see you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>