<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>drabble on Account for Everything Else</title>
    <link>http://itihas.review/tags/drabble/</link>
    <description>Recent content in drabble on Account for Everything Else</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 18:34:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://itihas.review/tags/drabble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 18:34:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/fear/</guid>
      <description>You know the greatest fear?
The greatest fear is thinking you once thought something that might have changed the world. It&amp;rsquo;s too terrible a truth to face up to. We shy away from it. But you see, I have. I have read the thoughts of people who looked to change it, who succeeded, if in nothing else, in leaving their mark. Many times they are people who did more. And I have thought what they thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Obsession</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/on-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/on-obsession/</guid>
      <description>She tried to picture the quiet of her meditation hall, timeless, without a beat, without a count, with only the steady progression of forms, the position and reposition of the body, every action of muscle corresponding to an action of breath. One began with palms flat against each other, fingers facing up, held against the sternum, pressing into the bone like a knife-edge lightly held in place; knees and back held straight, unmoving but relaxed, still but not rigid; feet together, facing forward, eyes as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation</title>
      <link>http://itihas.review/writing/conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://itihas.review/writing/conversation/</guid>
      <description>“Conversations always end too soon for me.”
“Do they now.”
I chewed on my lip, trying to frame my answer. “Either it&amp;rsquo;s awesome, it&amp;rsquo;s working, and the other person says it&amp;rsquo;s over out of the blue, or it just peters off, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where it went.” No, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t right. “It&amp;rsquo;s not that they&amp;rsquo;re silent, more that it stops working like it was.”
He seemed perfectly content to stand where he was, looking at me or through me as we went on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>