<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>horror story on Account for Everything Else</title>
    <link>https://itihas.review/tags/horror-story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in horror story on Account for Everything Else</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:21:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itihas.review/tags/horror-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Myth</title>
      <link>https://itihas.review/writing/myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itihas.review/writing/myth/</guid>
      <description>To what extent does what we hear about the world shape the way we speak to it? All our lives we’re fed fantasies of the perfect partner, the other half, the feelings of incompleteness that will not manifest until their resolution is immediately present; the problems that you didn’t know existed until their solution was manifest. This gross appropriation on the part of love of every other myth one can find oneself immersed in is nothing short of criminal at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposition</title>
      <link>https://itihas.review/writing/exposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itihas.review/writing/exposition/</guid>
      <description>She was pretty. She knew it, too, and used it shamelessly to her advantage whenever she thought it would give her the slightest edge in anything. Her face was well enough structured, but it was her skin, pale and creamy and only ever charmingly blemished, that did it for her; that and the way she used her face, the expressions. She was petite but healthy-bodied. She attracted attention, but not stares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preludes</title>
      <link>https://itihas.review/writing/preludes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 20:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itihas.review/writing/preludes/</guid>
      <description>The problem with the world today is a lack of destruction.
I say this despite knowing that most will find the notion perfectly counterintuitive – and that&amp;rsquo;s the problem: we have come to a place, in our collective psyche, where we find the necessity of destruction counterintuitive. This is far from a natural or healthy state.
Humans aren&amp;rsquo;t born with respect for only creative or preservative processes; we&amp;rsquo;re born without the barriers that tell us not to pull things down, to tear them apart, to kill them or crush them or stomp on them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>